Applying for Junior Position at your Company

Dear Hiring Manager,

I am applying for the Junior position for your company as advertised. I graduated from professional training at BCIT with a diploma in Computer Information Technology. I have an interest in software development, and I am looking for a position that will provide a challenge and a career job.

BCIT's intensive diploma program has provided me with industry-specific skills that can be applied immediately at your company. The program has included courses in CI/CD pipeline, agile project management methodologies, data analytics, cyber security, writing imperative bash scripts to provision service, developing microservices, and testing RESTful APIs. Although a majority of the work in these courses is completed independently, many labs and projects heavily focus on teamwork and collaboration.

There are 2 practicum experiences during the BCIT program, which were 15 weeks duration each practicum with weekly feedback from real clients, supervisors, or instructors. Under the agile methodology, the team and I built the software application, and to implement the results, we went through and discussed enough time clients' demands, technical support, technical issues, and possible solutions. During the projects, I mainly participated in development support, error fixing, and application testing. As a result of that, I could get the knowledge of how it is important readable coding skills and the development process of what I need to do at each stage. In addition, most individual projects during the BCIT program have focused on the SaaS environment. The final purpose of the project was to implement it as a service such as the backend, frontend, and database. In this environment, Docker, Ansible, and other cloud computing services were mainly used for it. I learned important interconnections between those such services. Overall, through my past experiences, I understood each service's process and got a strong concept of the development process.

Lastly, my previous work experiences have taught me the importance of team players about the overall success of a team. This especially became apparent during my time in the army in South Korea as the officer had a lot of responsibilities to fulfill. I was required to manage the unit of over a hundred soldiers carefully, and with the cooperation of other departments I successfully carried out the tasks and training. Good cooperation, teamwork, and leadership were the keys to accomplishing my military life efficiency.

I appreciate your consideration and hope my skills and experience align with your needs. And I look forward to any opportunity to show you how I can assist your company. I have attached my resume and would be happy to provide any additional information you might need, please contact me by e-mail at ryancho.hakhyeon@gmail.com or by phone at 604.349.8194 or you can check my information simply at https://ryanchoportfolio.netlify.app/ or https://ryanchoportfolio.netlify.app/ or https://ryanchohakhyeon.blog/

Sincerely, Ryan Hakhyeon Cho

Hakhyeon Cho (Ryan)

ryanchoportfolio.netlify.app

9868 Cameron St. Burnaby, BC, V3J 0A5 | +1 (604) 349 8194 | ryancho.hakhyeon@gmail.com

Profile

With military experience as the first lieutenant and college experience as an international student, I became a passionate learner who continually improves, has a strong sense of ownership and accountability in where I am, and a positive thinker who keeps an optimistic outlook for self-improvements. Now, I am ready to enhance my skills and knowledge in a place where I can contribute all of my efforts meaningfully.

SKILLS

- Programming languages: Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, Bash, Groovy
- Frontend / Backend: React, Angular, Node.js, Express.js, Flask, JSON, Nginx
- Database & Data Analysis: MySQL, MongoDB, SQLite, Pandas, Matplotlib, NumPy, R, Excel
- · Cloud Computing: Amazon AWS, Azure, Ansible, Docker, Kubernetes, Vagrant
- · Other tools: Jenkins, Jira, Windows & Web Server Admin, Agile Methodology, Troubleshooting

WORK HISTORY

Singular Hearing, BCIT Practicum

Sep. 2021 - Dec. 2021

- A 5-sprint client project for BCIT, ISSP(Industry Sponsored Student Project) Practicum Demo
- Tools: JavaScript, Linux-Anaconda, Git, Network
- Improved the backend to be more robust by the port-specific and the web servers such as Nginx.
- Developed features Various modes selection, A progress bar when the audio file is denoised, Displays of each type of denoised audio result that is downloadable, and A display bar comparing them with the original file.

City Studio Vancouver, BCIT Practicum

Jan. 2021 - Apr. 2021

- A 5-sprint client project for BCIT, ISSP(Industry Sponsored Student Project) Practicum Demo
- · Tools: Python, APIs, JSON, Open Database, Excel
- Implemented a Python app that scrapes data from open data portals for benchmarking purposes.
- Automated the Benchmarking Metrics application to process collecting data from public API.
- Deployed the components to create a fully automated application for data extraction.

PROJECTS

The CI/CD Environment System Design and Microservices

Jan. 2021 - Dec. 2021

- Tools: Jenkins, Gitlab, Docker, Kubernetes, Azure, Linux-Ubuntu, Python
- Designed the CI/CD environment system integration Jenkins, Gitlab, Apache on Azure Infrastructure.
- Leveraged cutting-edge tools such as Gitlab, Jenkins pipeline, and Groovy.
- Implemented a common CI/CD environment in multiple projects which is completely separated.
- · Built a microservices-based application in Python that each service is containerized.

Developing Application and Data Analysis

Sep. 2020 - Dec. 2021

- Designed object-oriented structure or MVC to develop an application such as an audio library, and flash games.
- Scraping data from general websites using crawling Python libraries Selenium, BeautifulSoup.
- Visualized and determined the prediction from organized datasets Pandas, Matpolib, Tableau, and Excel.

CERTIFICATION

AWS Certificated Cloud Practitioner Foundational Certification - Oct. 2023

Badge Link

FreeCodeCamp Certification - Scientific Computing & Data Analysis & Data Structures

EDUCATION

Computer Information Technology Diploma, British Columbia Institute of Technology - BCIT

Computer Software Development Bachelor, Semyung University, Korea(Republic of)

SPECIAL NOTES

Taekwondo for 10 years - 4th degree - Black Belt

Travel North America (14 Cities) for 2 months with a limited budget (\$1400)

Discharged Military Service - 2 years and a half as First Lieutenant (plus, 2 years R.O.T.C during University)